Guide to the Martin Shubik Papers, 1938-2017 and undated RL.01181
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Research and Notes, 1944-2004; undated; 1
  - Writings by Others, 1944-2004; undated; 3
    - Simon, J., Puig, C. and Aschoff, J., A Duopoly Simulation and Richer Theory, 1973 (Box 114)
    - Snyder, R., Robinson, J., National and International Decision-Making: A Report to the Committee on Research for Peace, 1961 (Box 157)
    - Stahl, I., The Use of Operational Gaming..., 1980 (Box 114)
    - Standish, D., The Art of Money, 1998 (Box 128)
    - Stern, G. Karreman, A., unidentified book, undated (Box 114)
    - Thorelli, B., et al., International Operations Simulation at the University of Chicago, 1962 (Box 128)
    - Trockel, W., The Chain Store Paradox Revisited, 1984 (Box 114)
    - Troubh, R., Purchased affection, 1976 (Box 128)
    - Unidentified author, The Geoffrey Hazard Short Course in Economics, undated (Box 114)
    - University of Massachusetts Amherst, Proceedings of the First International Conference on the Theory and Applications of Differential Games, 1969 (Box 157)
    - Various authors, Omni (superiority of female brain, x-ray holograms, consciousness, and the split brain), 1983 (Box 114)
    - Viner, J., A Modest Proposal for Some Stress on Scholarship in Graduate Training, 1953 (Box 157)
    - Whitman, M., Merger Proxy Statements and Exchange Prospectuses, 1973 (Box 114)
    - Why People Play Games, 1969 (Box 128)
    - Wickham, S., Concentration et Dimensions, 1966 (Box 159)
    - Widdowson, E., Definitions and Forumulae for Students: Modern Physics (Box 157)
    - Wold, H., Mergers of Economics and Philosophy of Science (signed reprint), 1969 (Box 114)
    - 运筹与管理, Chinese Version of the 50th Anniversary Issue of Operations Research and Management Science, 2004 (Box 160)
    - Академия наук СССР. Центральный экономико-математический институт., Деловые игры и их программное обеспечение (материалы конференции), 1976 (Box 158)
    - Ваисборд, Э.М., Жуковский, В.И., ВВедение в дифференциальные игры нескольких лиц и их приложения, 1980 (Box 158)
    - Воробьев, Н.Н., редактор., Теория игр: аннотированный указатель отечественной и зарубежной литературы за 1969-1974 гг., 1980 (Box 158)
    - Воробьев, Н.Н., редактор., Теория игр: аннотированный указатель публикаций по 1968 г., 1976 (Box 158)
    - Воробьев, Н.Н., Основы теории игр: бескоалиционные игры, 1984 (Box 158)
    - Воробьев, Н.Н., Теория игр: для экономистов-кибернетиков, 1985 (Box 158)
    - Воробьев, Н.Н., Приложения теории игр, 1971 (Box 158)
    - Вилкас, Э., редактор., Успехи теории игр: труды ИИ Всесоюзной конференции по теории игр (Вильнюс, 1971), 1973 (Box 158)
    - Суздаль, В.Г., Теория игр для флота, 1976 (Box 158)
    - Ерешко, Ф.И., Математика Конфликта и сотрудничества, 1973 (Box 158)
    - Митягин, Б.С., редактор., Математическая экономика и функциональный анализ, 1974 (Box 158)
    - Министерство Высшего и среднего специального образования УССР, III Всесоюзная конференция по теории игр, 10-12 сентября 1974 годь: Тезисы докладов (Box 158)
    - Институт физики и математики ан литовской ССР, Математические методы в социальных науках, Выпуск 1-9, 1972-1977 (Box 158)
- Writings, 1951-2016; undated; 1
  This series contains copies, reprints, drafts, notes, and other documents associated with Shubik's published works. These include: reprints and copies of published journal articles and book chapters; books; and documents from his referee activity for academic journals and publishers.
  - Indexed Papers, 1952-2008; 1
    This subseries includes published papers assigned an index number from an enumerated list in Shubik's CV and arranged by index number.
    - Nos. 1-18 (Box 56)
    - No. 19 (drafts, notes) (Box 56)
    - Nos. 20-21 (Box 56)
    - No. 22 (referee report) (Box 56)
    - Nos. 23-34 (Box 56)
    - No. 39 (draft) (Box 56)
    - Nos. 40-43 (Box 56)
    - No. 45 (typed manuscript with revisions) (Box 56)
    - Nos. 46-48 (Box 56)
    - No. 49 (correspondence) (Box 56)
    - Nos. 50-58 (Box 56)
    - No. 59 (notes, drafts) (Box 56)
    - Nos. 61-62 (Box 56)
    - No. 64 (galley, no reprint) (Box 56)
    - Nos. 66-67 (Box 57)
    - No. 68 (draft) (Box 57)
    - Nos. 70-71 (Box 57)
    - No. 72 (draft) (Box 57)
    - No. 73 (Box 57)
    - No. 74 (draft) (Box 57)
    - No. 75 (draft) (Box 57)
    - Nos. 76-90 (Box 57)
    - No. 91 (draft) (Box 57)
    - Nos. 92-94 (Box 57)
    - No. 95 (draft) (Box 57)
    - Nos. 96-105 (Box 57)
    - No. 106 (draft, typed manuscript), 2 folders (Box 57)
    - Nos. 107-119 (Box 57)
    - No. 120 (Box 57)
    - Nos. 121-131 (Box 58)
    - No. 132 (notes, drafts, research, CFDP, no reprint) (Box 58)
    - Nos. 134-137 (Box 58)
    - No. 138 (working paper) (Box 58)
    - Nos. 139-150 (Box 58)
    - No. 151 (draft) (Box 58)
    - Nos. 152-159 (Box 58)
    - No. 160 (typed manuscript) (Box 58)
    - No. 161 (typed manuscript) (Box 58)
    - Nos. 163-164 (Box 58)
    - No. 165 (handwritten draft, photocopy of working paper, no reprint) (Box 58)
    - No. 166 (typed manuscript) (Box 58)
    - No. 167 (Box 58)
    - No. 168 (handwritten draft) (Box 58)
    - No. 169 (Box 58)
    - No. 170 (galley) (Box 58)
    - Nos. 171-176 (Box 58)
    - No. 179 (working paper, no reprint) (Box 59)
    - No. 180 (drafts, notes, no reprint) (Box 59)
    - No. 183 (Box 59)
    - No. 184 (working paper, no reprint) (Box 59)
    - No. 185 (typed manuscript, no reprint) (Box 59)
    - Nos. 188-189 (Box 59)
    - No. 190 (drafts, no reprint) (Box 59)
    - No. 191 (Box 59)
    - No. 193 (draft, no reprint) (Box 59)
    - No. 195 (draft) (Box 59)
    - No. 197 (preliminary paper) (Box 59)
    - No. 199 (handwritten draft, book reviews, correspondence, no reprint) (Box 59)
    - No. 200 (Box 59)
    - No. 202 (galley) (Box 59)
    - No. 206 (written draft, typed manuscript, correspondence), 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Nos. 207-209 (Box 59)
    - No. 210 (revisions, correspondence, working paper, no reprint) (Box 59)
    - No. 212 (typed manuscript, no reprint) (Box 59)
    - No. 213 (typed manuscript) (Box 59)
    - No. 214 (drafts, working paper) (Box 60)
    - No. 215 (Box 60)
    - No. 217 (revised proof, correspondence) (Box 60)
    - No. 219 (Box 60)
    - No. 220 (CFDP working paper, Institute for Decision Sciences working paper, correspondence, no reprint) (Box 60)
    - No. 221 (working paper) (Box 60)
    - No. 222 (Box 60)
    - No. 223 (typed draft with revision, correspondence (Box 60)
    - No. 224 (proof) (Box 60)
    - No. 225 (proof, correspondence, draft) (Box 60)
    - No. 226 (no reprint) (Box 60)
    - No. 227 (Box 60)
    - No. 228 (draft, correspondence, working paper) (Box 60)
    - No. 229 (draft, correspondence, no reprint) (Box 60)
    - No. 230 (typed manuscript, correspondence, report) (Box 60)
    - No. 231 (working paper, drafts, notes) (Box 60)
    - No. 233 (drafts, discussion paper) (Box 61)
    - No. 234 (working paper) (Box 61)
    - No. 235 (revised proof, notes, drafts, correspondence), 4 folders (Box 61)
    - No. 236 (Box 61)
    - No. 238 (working paper) (Box 61)
    - No. 239 (working report, drafts, correspondence), 3 folders (Box 61)
    - No. 240 (working paper, notes, correspondence), 1 folder (Box 61)
    - No. 240 (working paper, notes, correspondence), 2 folders (Box 62)
    - No. 241 (typed manuscript, draft, correspondence, no reprint), 2 folders (Box 62)
    - No. 243 (working paper, draft) (Box 62)
    - No. 244 (working paper, manuscripts, drafts, research notes, correspondence, no reprint), 2 folders (Box 62)
    - No. 245 (manuscript, notes, drafts, revised draft, correspondence, no reprint), 3 folders (Box 62)
    - No. 245 (manuscript, notes, drafts, revised draft, correspondence, no reprint), 1 folder (Box 63)
    - No. 246 (final draft, correspondence, no reprint) (Box 63)
    - No. 247 (typed manuscript, draft, correspondence) (Box 63)
    - No. 249 and No. 255 (typed manuscript, drafts, revisions, no reprint) (Box 63)
    - No. 250 (typed manuscript, student report, no reprint) (Box 63)
    - No. 251 (typed manuscript) (Box 63)
    - No. 254 (drafts, research notes, correspondence, no reprint) (Box 63)
    - No. 255 (typed manuscript, no reprint) (Box 63)
    - No. 256 (typed manuscript, drafts, no reprint), 2 folders (Box 63)
    - No. 260 (typed manuscript, working paper) (Box 63)
    - No. 266 (typed manuscript, typed manuscript with revisions, no reprint) (Box 63)
    - No. 266 (typed manuscript, no reprint) (Box 64)
    - No. 267 (Box 64)
    - No. 268 (Box 64)
    - No. 269 (galley, no reprint) (Box 64)
    - No. 271 (working draft, correspondence, no reprint) (Box 64)
    - No. 273 (Box 64)
    - No. 274 (drafts, CFDP, correspondence, no reprint), 2 folders (Box 64)
    - No. 277 (working paper, no reprint) (Box 64)
    - No. 279 (proof, no reprint) (Box 64)
    - No. 281 (Box 64)
    - No. 282 (typed manuscript, no reprint) (Box 64)
    - No. 287 (Box 64)
    - No. 288 (referee report) (Box 64)
    - No. 290 (Box 64)
    - No. 291 (correspondence) (Box 64)
    - Nos. 293-294 (Box 64)
    - Nos. 295-306 (Box 64)
  - Cowles Papers, 1960-2005; 2
    This subseries contains Shubik's papers that are included in the Cowles Foundation Discussion Papers and Research Reports series. Papers are arranged by Cowles's assigned index numbers.
    - Cowles Foundation Discussion Paper (CFDP), Nos. 100-104 (Box 65)
    - CFDP No. 105 (typed draft) (Box 65)
    - CFDP Nos. 107-167 (Box 65)
    - CFDP No. 170 (typed draft) (Box 65)
    - CFDP Nos. 180-208 (Box 65)
    - CFDP Nos. 217-230 (Box 65)
    - CFDP No. 233 (referee report) (Box 65)
    - CFDP Nos. 236-240 (Box 65)
    - CFDP No. 247 (early draft, revisions) (Box 65)
    - CFDP No. 249 (Box 66)
    - CFDP No. 270 (referee report) (Box 66)
    - CFDP Nos. 274-289 (Box 66)
    - CFDP Nos. 316-330 (Box 66)
    - CFDP No. 334 (revisions, notes) (Box 66)
    - CFDP Nos. 331-338 (Box 66)
    - CFDP Nos. 347-364 (Box 66)
    - CFDP Nos. 365-374 (Box 66)
    - CFDP Nos. 377-410R (Box 66)
    - CFDP Nos. 414-429 (Box 67)
    - CFDP Nos. 431-448 (Box 67)
    - CFDP Nos. 454-460R (Box 67)
    - CFDP Nos. 462-476 (Box 67)
    - CFDP Nos. 478-484 (Box 67)
    - CFDP Nos. 507-525 (Box 68)
    - CFDP No. 557 (correspondence, referee reports) (Box 68)
    - CFDP Nos. 559-619 (Box 68)
    - CFDP No.627 (working draft, correspondence), 2 folders (Box 68)
    - CFDP Nos. 634R-706 (Box 68)
    - CFDP Nos. 712-733 (Box 68)
    - CFDP No. 744 (handwritten drafts) (Box 68)
    - CFDP Nos. 747R-787 (Box 69)
    - CFDP No. 789 (typed draft) (Box 69)
    - CFDP Nos. 804-814 (Box 69)
    - CFDP No. 814R (drafts, handwritten drafts) (Box 69)
    - CFDP Nos. 841-871 (Box 69)
    - CFDP No. 879 (Box 69)
    - CFDP Nos. 879R (early manuscript) (Box 69)
    - CFDP No. 891 (typed manuscript) (Box 69)
    - CFDP Nos. 895-964 (Box 69)
    - CFDP Nos. 996-1037 (Box 70)
    - CFDP No. 1040 (notes, correspondence) (Box 70)
    - CFDP No. 1043 (Box 70)
    - CFDP No. 1046 (drafts, correspondence) (Box 70)
    - CFDP Nos. 1056-1076 (Box 70)
    - CFDP No. 1050 (notes, drafts) (Box 70)
    - CFDP No. 1088 and No. 1095 (correspondence, summary), 2 folders (Box 70)
    - CFDP No. 1089 and No. 1088 (research) (Box 70)
    - CFDP No. 1094 (summary) (Box 70)
    - CFDP No. 1099 (revised draft, correspondence) (Box 70)
    - CFDP Nos. 1112-1132 (Box 70)
    - CFDP No. 1156 (Santa Fe Working Paper, draft with notes, revised manuscript, early draft), 5 folders (Box 71)
    - CFDP Nos. 1174-1184 (Box 71)
    - CFDP No. 1202 (Box 71)
    - CFDP No. 1253 (drafts, revisions, notes, Santa Fe Working Paper), 2 folders (Box 71)
    - CFDP No. 1304 (Box 71)
    - CFDP No. 1343 (Box 71)
    - CFDP No. 1396 (typed manuscript, draft, correspondence), 3 folders (Box 71)
    - CFDP No. 1413 (final copy with activity report) (Box 71)
    - CFDP No. 1414 (Box 72)
    - CFDP No. 1424 (typed manuscript with revisions, draft with notes, correspondence), 3 folders (Box 72)
    - CFDP No. 1439 (corrections copy) (Box 72)
    - CFDP Nos. 1455 and 1460 (drafts, notes, no final report), 3 folders (Box 72)
    - CFDP Unidentified number: Game Theory, Complexity and Simplicity, Part II, 1997 (Box 72)
    - Cowles Foundation Report (CFR), Nos. 250-359 (Box 72)
    - CFR Nos. 363-447 (Box 72)
    - CFR Nos. 450-578 (Box 72)
    - CFR Nos. 584-731 (Box 73)
    - CFR Nos. 741-1049 (Box 73)
  - Articles, Book Chapters, and Other Papers, 1951-2016; undated; 3
    This subseries includes journal articles, book chapters, and other scholarly writings by Shubik, arranged alphabetically by title.
    - A Biographical Model of Migration, 1994 (Box 106)
    - A Bound on the number of Nash Equilibria in a Coordination Game, undated (Box 126)
    - A Comparison between some Features of a Purely Competitive Market, 1956 (Box 107)
    - A Comparison of Six Simple Models of Production and Exchange with Sahi, S., undated (Box 107)
    - A Dynamic Strategic Market Game with Limited Borrowing... (draft with notes), 1982 (Box 107)
    - A Fond Remembrance of Per Bax, 2002 (Box 107)
    - A Game Theoretic Approach to the Theory of Money…, 1988 (Box 108)
    - A Graphic Examination of Trade with the Commodities and a money and three competitive equilibria (Box 125)
    - A Note on Budget Allocation Games without Side Payments, 1996 (Box 109)
    - A Note on Liquidity and Velocity, 2003 (Box 126)
    - A Note on Paper Gold, undated (Box 109)
    - A Note on the Egalitarian Selection of a Competitive Equilibrium…, 1983 (Box 109)
    - A Note on the Relationship between the Value and the Competitive Equilibrium, undated (Box 109)
    - A Note on the Unique Minimal Loan Equilibrium in an Exchange Economy, undated (Box 109)
    - A One Period Exchange Economy with a Mutual Band and Redemption in Gold, 1990 (Box 109)
    - A Personal Rememberance of John Forbes Nash Jr., undated (Box 128)
      Includes draft
    - A Program in the Study of Dynamic Monetary Economies, 1991 (Box 109)
    - A Sketch of a Theory of Money and Financial Institutions, 2003 (Box 126)
    - A Sketch on the Development of Money and Financial Institutions, c. 1984 (Box 124)
    - A Stochastic Overlapping Generations Economy with inheritance, 2000 (Box 126)
    - A Strategic Market Game with Active Bankruptcy, 1999 (Box 128)
      Includes related correspondence
    - A Strategic Market Game with Limited Borrowing and Exogenous Uncertainty, 1982 (Box 110)
    - A Theory of Money and Banking in a General Equilibrium System, 1970 (Box 110)
    - A Trading Model to Avoid Tatonnement Metaphysics, 1975 (Box 110)
    - A Two Party System with Government, Bureaucracy, and Mass Voting, 1982; 2 folders (Box 110)
    - A Unified Model of Quantity, Price, and Price-Quantity Duopoly, undated (Box 111)
    - A Visit to the Soviet Union, undated (Box 125)
    - Absenteeism, substitute, and complements in simple games, 2004 (Box 128)
      Includes referee reports
    - Accepted Manuscript: From General Equilibrium to Schumpeter, 2015 (Box 126)
    - Accepting Orders for a Job Shop... (typed manuscript), 1957 (Box 106)
    - Accounting and Economic Theory, 2003 (Box 106)
    - Accounting Theory and its Relationship to General Equilibrium Theory, 1992 (Box 106)
    - Adam Crusoe's GNP, Welfare and Money Supply, undated (Box 106)
    - American Economic Review, May 1999; 2008 (Box 126)
      Includes correspondence pertaining to multiple submissions to the journal
    - An Experiment with Ten Duopoly Games and Beat-the-Average Behaviour, 1971 (Box 128)
      Includes working paper
    - An Infinite Horizon Strategic Market Game with Fiat Money, Part II with Karatzas, I. and Sudderth, W., 1992 (Box 108)
    - An Informal Guide to Some Papers of a Theory of Money and Financial Institutions, 1977 (Box 108)
    - An OLG Economy with Stochastic Individual Income, Part I with Karatzas, I. and Sudderth, W., 1999 (Box 109)
    - Applications of Game Theory, 1960; 1970 (Box 126)
    - Applied General Equilibrium Computations and Strategic Market Games with Rutherford, T., undated (Box 106)
    - Auctions, Bidding and Contracting, undated (Box 106)
    - Babylonian Economics Exhibit, 2000 (Box 106)
    - Bankruptcy Laws and the Firm's Financial Decision, undated (Box 128)
    - Barrons, 1983 (Box 106)
    - Behavior, Society and Nuclear War, Vol. II (unpublished chapter, correspondence), undated (Box 104)
      Includes unpublished writing
    - Behavioral Approach to a Strategic Market Game, undated (Box 125)
      Draft, correspondence with Nick Vriend
    - Bertrand, Joseph (New Palgrave entry), 1985 (Box 106)
    - Birth Processes and Intergenerational Transfers with Arthur, W., undated (Box 106)
    - Book contracts, 1980s (Box 50)
    - Book review, miscellaneous writings, 1977; 1985; 1998; 2011 (Box 126)
    - Book Reviews by Shubik, 1959 (Box 124)
    - Book Reviews by Shubik, undated; 2 folders (Box 106)
    - Book Reviews of Gaming Literature and Allied Topics with Brewer, G., 1971 (Box 106)
    - Budgets in a Decentralized Organization with Incomplete Information, 1970 (Box 106)
    - Business Review Weekly, 2004 (Box 126)
      Includes correspondence related to article written by Shubik
    - Business Week: Economics, 1958 (Box 126)
    - Can We Manage With(out) Markets?, Q2, 2007 (Box 124)
    - Capital Markets, Efficiency and Corporate Control, undated (Box 106)
    - Center for Competitive and Conflict Systems, Report #8, 1984-1985 (Box 107)
    - Comments on Some Experiments Non-Constant-Sum Games Revisited, undated (Box 128)
    - Competition or Cooperation on NASDAQ, 1996 (Box 107)
    - Containing Cost Growth in Defense Procurement (typed manuscript), undated (Box 107)
    - Control of Dividends, Capital Subscriptions, and Physical Inventories, 1997 (Box 126)
    - Control of Dividends, Capital Subscriptions, and Physical Inventories, 2012 (Box 128)
      Includes referee reports and related correspondence
    - Control of Dividends, Capital Subscriptions, and Physical Inventories with Li, Lode, Sobel, 2003 (Box 107)
    - Cooperative Games (correspondence), 1985 (Box 107)
    - Corporate Control, Efficient Markets, the Public Good, the Law and Economic Theory, undated (Box 107)
    - Corporate Reality and Accounting for Investors with Whitman, M., 1972 (Box 107)
    - Costly Search, Local Maxima and Matrix Games with Lee, J., 1993 (Box 107)
    - Cournot, Antoine Augustin, 1985 (Box 107)
    - Crisis Stability Games, 1993 (Box 128)
      Includes reprint
    - Crisis Stability Games with Bracken, J., 1990 (Box 107)
    - Default and Punishment in General Equilibrium, 2001 (Box 126)
    - Design for Forecasting, 1957 (Box 107)
    - Development: Models, Simulations, and Games, 1970 (Box 107)
    - Donald Trump and the Reichstag, 2016 (Box 126)
    - Econometrica, May 2001; Feb 2002 (Box 126)
      Includes correspondence related to multiple submissions to journal
    - Economic Consequences of Missile Defense with Bracken, P., 2001 (Box 107)
    - Editor's report: A Stochastic Overlapping Generations Economy with Inheritance, 2001 (Box 126)
    - ELSEVIER, 2001 (Box 126)
      Include correspondence related to contributing chapter to Handbook of Game Theory, vol. 3
    - Fiat Money in a Mass Market with Whitt, W., 1971-1972 (Box 107)
    - Financial Economics, 1985 (Box 123)
    - Financial Systems: Instabilities and Conflict, 1995 (Box 107)
    - Financial Systems: Instabilities and Conflict, 1995 (Box 128)
    - Financing of Public Goods through Taxation in a General Equilibrium Economy, 2016 (Box 128)
      Includes referee reports and response to editor comments
    - Financing Trade and the Price Level: Problems with the Description of Markets, Expectations, Money and Credit, 1994 (Box 128)
    - Financing Trade and the Price Level…, 1994 (Box 107)
    - Game Theory, undated (Box 108)
    - Game Theory (unpublished manuscript), undated; 2 folders (Box 104)
    - Game Theory and Operations Research Sixty Years Later, undated (Box 108)
    - Game Theory and Operations Research: Some Musings 50 Years Later, 2002 (Box 108)
    - Game Theory and Princeton, undated (Box 108)
    - Game Theory: The Language of Strategy, 1981 (Box 108)
    - Games of Status and Wealth and Status Part II: A Game Theoretic Approach, 1997 (Box 126)
    - Games of Status and Wealth and Status…, 1996-1997 (Box 108)
    - Games of Status Part I: Modeling considerations, 1996 (Box 126)
    - Gaming, 1993 (Box 108)
    - Gaming Literature Review with Brewer, G., Savage, E., 1971; 2 folders (Box 108)
    - Inefficiency of Nash equilibria with incomplete information, 2012 (Box 128)
    - Inflationary Bias in a Simply Stochastic Economy, 2002 (Box 128)
    - Information, Duopoly and Competitive Markets A Sensitivity Analysis, 1972 (Box 128)
    - Information, Theories of Competition and Theory of Games, 1951 (Box 108)
    - Intergenerational Political Economy (drafts), 1980 (Box 108)
    - International Security and the Theory of Games, 1990 (Box 126)
    - Interviews with Shubik, undated (Box 52)
    - Introduction to the Special Issue of Games and Economic Behavior in honor of Martin Shubik, 2009 (Box 126)
    - Involved Parties, Incentives and Process, 1976 (Box 108)
    - Is Economics the Next Physical Science, 2005 (Box 128)
    - Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 1999 (Box 126)
      Includes letter submitting article to journal
    - Journal of Mathematical Economics, special section in honor of M. Shubik, 2009 (Box 52)
    - Journal of Public Economic Theory, 2011 (Box 126)
    - Kohlberg's Critique of Perfect Equilibrium, undated (Box 108)
    - Macro-Modelling, Default and Money, 2013 (Box 128)
      Includes draft and referee reports
    - Market Bubbles and Wasteful Avoidance: Tax and Regulatory Constraints on Short Sales, 2003 (Box 128)
    - Market Share, Competition among Firms... with Bak, P., Maslov, S., Karatzas, Y., Sudderth, W., 1996 (Box 108)
    - Market Structure and Behavior, 1980 (Box 128)
    - Mathematical Economics, 1986 (Box 108)
    - Mathematical Institutional Economics, 2005 (Box 128)
      Includes draft and notes
    - Microeconomic Analysis, (unpublished manuscript), undated; 2 folders (Box 104)
    - MIEconomics, 2012 (Box 126)
    - Minimally complex exchange mechanisms, 2014 (Box 126)
    - Minimally Complex Exchange Mechanisms: Emergence of Prices, Markets, and Money, 2014 (Box 128)
      Includes working paper and associated presentation
    - Miscellaneous Papers binder, 1970-1972; 3 folders (Box 123)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 2002; 2005 (Box 126)
    - Model of Strategic Behavior and Nuclear Deterrence, 1992 (Box 108)
    - Money and the Monetization of Credit, undated (Box 108)
    - Money as an Asset and the Role of Clearing Houses, 1995 (Box 109)
    - Money as Insurance, 1983 (Box 109)
    - Money as Minimal Complexity, 2015 (Box 126)
    - Money as Minimal Complexity, undated (Box 125)
    - Money Core, undated (Box 125)
    - Monopolistic and Oligopolistic Banking, 2005 (Box 126)
    - MTH&TT, 2012 (Box 126)
    - Names of the Games, 1990 (Box 128)
      Includes working paper and referee reports
    - Nation State of Siberia in 2020, undated (Box 123)
    - Newspaper article with G. Brewer regarding Cape Hatteras Lighthouse, North Carolina, 1987 (Box 49)
    - Newspaper article, Los Costos del bioterrorismos, containing analysis by Shubik, 2001 (Box 52)
    - Normative Estimates about how to Settle Three Person Cooperative Games, 1991 (Box 109)
    - Notes of the Business Game 1972 Data, 1983 (Box 109)
    - Notes on an Experimental Evaluation of Four Leading Delicatessens with Madansky, A., 1976 (Box 109)
    - Objectivity, Spite, Revenge, and "Rational Play", undated (Box 128)
    - Observations on the Vietnam War (draft), 1968 (Box 109)
    - On Coalition Games (ISAC working paper), undated (Box 107)